You've reached lesson two of our data wrangling course.
لقد وصلتم إلى الدرس الثاني من دورة تعارض البيانات.
In lesson one, we walk through the whole wrangling process from gathering,
في الدرس الأول، لقد اطلعنا على عملية التعارض بالكامل بدءًا من التجميع،
to assessing, to cleaning data,
مرورًا بالتقييم، وصوولًا إلى مسح البيانات،
and iterating if necessary.
وتكرارها عند الضرورة.
In the next three lessons, you're going to dive deeper into each step of the process.
في الدروس الثلاثة التالية، ستتناولون كل خطوة من هذه العملية بالتفصيل.
First, you're going to master gathering data.
ستتقنون أولًا جمع البيانات.
Depending on your project,
وحسب مشروعكم،
gathering data varies a lot.
سيختلف جمع البيانات كثيرًا.
Data you need may be spread across dozens of sources and in different file formats,
تنتشر البيانات التي تحتاجونها عبر العديد من المصادر وبتنسيقات مختلفة،
which might be the most challenging part of working with data.
وهذا الجزء ربما يكون الجزء الأصعب في التعامل مع البيانات.
Not analyzing, not visualizing,
لا تكمن الصعوبة في التحليل ولا في التصوير،
not even building fancy machine-learning models, simply gathering.
ولا حتى في إنشاء نماذج تعلم الآلة الهائلة، إنما تكمن ببساطة في التجميع.
It's also glossed over in most data wrangling courses where
يتم توضيحه في معظم دورات تعارض البيانات
complete datasets are just provided for you. Not here.
التي تُقدم لكم فيها مجموعات البيانات الكاملة. وليس هنا.
In this lesson, you'll gather real data from several different sources and
في هذا الدرس، ستجمعون بيانات حقيقية من عدة مصادر مختلفة
file formats while learning about each and how to handle them using Python.
وبتنسيقات مختلفة في حين تعلم المزيد عن كل واحد وطريقة التعامل معها باستخدام Python.
You'll combine them all to create a master dataset which we'll then use
ستجمعونها جميعًا لإنشاء مجموعة بيانات أصلية سنستخدمها بعد ذلك
to answer interesting questions and produce stunning visualizations.
للإجابة عن الأسئلة التي تثير اهتمامنا وإنشاء مرئيات مذهلة.
You're going to leave this lesson with the gathering skills required
ستتعلمون في هذا الدرس مهارات التجميع المطلوبة
for the vast majority of your wrangling projects in the future.
للغالبية العظمى من المشروعات المتعارضة فيما يلي.
So let's do this. This is going to be fun,
حسنًا، لنقم بذلك. كم سيكون هذا ممتعًا،
challenging, and is going to require a bit of creativity.
وصعبًا، وسيتطلب قليلًا من الأفكار الإبداعية.